<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courses><course><academic_department_code>JAZZ</academic_department_code>

<academic_department_name></academic_department_name>

<subject_area_code>JAZZ</subject_area_code>

<subject_area_name>Jass Studies</subject_area_name>

<school_bulletin_prefix_code_1>W</school_bulletin_prefix_code_1>

<course_number_1>4900</course_number_1>

<course_term_offered_1>y</course_term_offered_1>

<school_bulletin_prefix_code_2></school_bulletin_prefix_code_2>

<course_number_2></course_number_2>

<course_term_offered_2></course_term_offered_2>

<course_section_code>0</course_section_code>

<course_identifier_cooked>JAZZ W4900y</course_identifier_cooked>

<course_name>TOPICS IN JAZZ STUDIES: JAZZ &#38; THE LITERARY IMAGINATION</course_name>

<course_points_min>3</course_points_min>

<course_points_max>0</course_points_max>

<course_points_notes></course_points_notes>

<course_points_cooked>3 pts.</course_points_cooked>

<course_preface></course_preface>

<course_description>This course will focus on the ways that jazz has been a source of inspiration for a variety of twentieth-century literatures, from the blues poetry of the Harlem Renaissance to contemporary fiction. We will consider in detail the ways that writers have discovered or intuited formal models and political implications in black music. Rather than simply assume that influence only travels in one direction, we will also take up some literary efforts (including autobiography, poetry, historiography, and criticism) by musicians themselves. What are the links between musical form and literary innovation? How can terms of musical analysis (improvisation, rhythm, syncopation, harmony) be applied to the medium of writing? How does music suggest modes of social interaction or political potential to be articulated in language? How does one evaluate the performance of a poem (in an oral recitation or musical setting) in relation to its text? Materials may include writings and recordings by Jacques Attali, James Weldon Johnson, Langston Hughes, Louis Armstrong, Zora Neale Hurston, Sterling Brown, Roland Barthes, Ralph Ellison, Amiri Baraka, Charles Mingus, Ella Fitzgerald, Edward Kamau Brathwaite, Gayl Jones, Michael Ondaatje, Joseph Jarman, Nathaniel Mackey, and Harryette Mullen, among others. Requirements for undergraduates: &#38;nbsp; regular attendance; weekly response papers (1 page maximum); one midterm paper (6-8 pages); and one final paper (10-12 pages).</course_description>

<corequisites></corequisites>

<prerequisites></prerequisites>

<not_offered_flag>Y</not_offered_flag>

<course_bulletins>BC, CC, GS, GSAS, SOA</course_bulletins>

<course_populations></course_populations>

<course_instructors_actual>Instructor To Be Announced</course_instructors_actual>

<course_instructors_expected>Brent Edwards</course_instructors_expected>

<course_instructors_full>B. Edwards</course_instructors_full>

</course></courses>