<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courses><course><academic_department_code>LAWC</academic_department_code>

<academic_department_name></academic_department_name>

<subject_area_code>LAW</subject_area_code>

<subject_area_name>Law</subject_area_name>

<school_bulletin_prefix_code_1>S</school_bulletin_prefix_code_1>

<course_number_1>3200</course_number_1>

<course_term_offered_1>z</course_term_offered_1>

<school_bulletin_prefix_code_2></school_bulletin_prefix_code_2>

<course_number_2></course_number_2>

<course_term_offered_2></course_term_offered_2>

<course_section_code>0</course_section_code>

<course_identifier_cooked>LAW S3200z</course_identifier_cooked>

<course_name>Constitutional Crises on Campus: Constitutional Law through the Lens of Higher Education</course_name>

<course_points_min>3</course_points_min>

<course_points_max>0</course_points_max>

<course_points_notes></course_points_notes>

<course_points_cooked>3 pts.</course_points_cooked>

<course_preface></course_preface>

<course_description>The intricacies of the most controversial aspects of the American Constitution play out daily on college campuses across the country. Who gets admitted to elite institutions, and what factors should they consider? Faculties have tenure to protect their right to challenge conventional wisdom, but what exactly does Academic Freedom protect? Students have the right to free speech, or do they? Can a college censor a student newspaper? If a student is disciplined on campus, do they have a right to an attorney? Do students have a property interest in their education that can cost over $100,000? How does the law treat private and public institutions differently? This course is designed to explore the most controversial of constitutional topics including the First Amendment right to free speech, the Fifth Amendment&#39;s takings clause, the Sixth Amendment right to counsel, and the Fourteenth Amendment&#39;s guarantee of equal protection, procedural due process and substantive due process in regards to life, liberty, and property.</course_description>

<corequisites></corequisites>

<prerequisites></prerequisites>

<not_offered_flag>N</not_offered_flag>

<course_bulletins>CEST</course_bulletins>

<course_populations></course_populations>

<course_instructors_actual>Instructor To Be Announced</course_instructors_actual>

<course_instructors_expected></course_instructors_expected>

<course_instructors_full>Instructor To Be Announced</course_instructors_full>

</course></courses>